playlist.com 2012-06-07

# Playlist | Privacy Policy

## Last Updated: February 21, 2012

### Our Commitment to Your Privacy

This site is operated by Project Playlist, Inc. (“Playlist”). At Playlist, we understand that you value your privacy, and we want to help make your experience with our site, software, and services (referred to in this policy collectively as our “services”) satisfying and safe. This policy describes our collection of information, including personal information, in connection with our services, and explains how we use and disclose this information. To make this policy easy to find, we make it available from our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

### Personal Information We Collect and How We Use It

**"Personal information,"** as used in this policy, is information that may be used to identify an individual, such as name or email address. We collect personal information in the course of providing our services to you and you may also make personal information available to others as you use the services. Below are some examples of the types of personal information we collect and the ways in which we use it:

Information you provide - We collect personal information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions, such as via the use of email and our download forms used to download tools. We use personal information we collect to respond to your inquiry or request, to provide, improve, and develop our services, to tailor your user experience, to prevent or investigate fraudulent or inappropriate usage of our services, to enable you to participate in contests and promotions, for research and development and for the other purposes described in this policy. Depending on your settings, certain information you provide may be available to other users.

In addition, we may use or transfer your email address to deliver targeted marketing messages from us, our subsidiaries, affiliated companies, and other trusted businesses. You may opt-out from receiving these marketing messages by following the instructions provided in the messages. You may also provide personal information to us in other ways, such as by requesting user support.

Information from third parties - We may receive personal information from third parties about their users, and may combine this information with other personal information we maintain about you. If we do so, this policy governs the combined information.

### Non-Personal Information

We may also collect information that is not personally identifiable, and may aggregate personal information or otherwise render it anonymous (that is, non-personally identifiable). We use non-personally identifiable information we collect to operate our network, to provide, improve, and develop our services, to tailor your user experience, to prevent or investigate fraudulent or inappropriate usage of our services, to enable you to participate in contests and promotions, for research and development and for the other purposes described in this policy. We may use this anonymous information for various purposes and may share it with third parties. Below are some examples of the types of non-personal information we collect and some specific examples of how we use this information:

Usage tracking - We may collect non-personal information from your use of our services. For example, we may collect information about user traffic and usage patterns throughout our site, and similar information regarding the use of our software and services. We may also track click-through information, such as IP addresses, from the messages we send to our users. We use the information we collect in these manners to, for example, improve our services, to develop new products and services, to gauge the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns, to discourage and address abusive and fraudulent use of our services, and to help our users with troubleshooting issues. Click here <http://www.nielsen-netratings.com/privacy/sitecensus.htm> to learn more information about how we use a third party service with cookies (flash and non-flash) and web beacons to collect and use information on this Web site.

Cookies - When you visit our site, we or our advertisers may send one or more cookies - a small file containing a string of characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser, or recognize a cookie that is already on your machine. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences and tracking user trends, and to customize your experience. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

Playlists and streams - We may use general information about our members’ playlists or streaming activity that help our advertisers understand the musical tastes of our members. Our advertisers may use the information that we provide in order to direct certain types of ads to specific pages where users may have expected interest in the product.

If we directly combine any non-personal information gathered through passive means with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information under this policy. Otherwise, we use information collected by passive means in aggregated or other non-personally identifiable forms.

### Disclosure of Personal and Other Information

We may provide personal information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies, and other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of providing our services, so they may also offer you their products and services, and for other purposes described in this policy. We limit the personal information shared with these third parties to that which is necessary to carry out those functions and require that our partners respect and comply with applicable law as a condition of doing business with them. Except as described in this policy, we will not provide your personal information to third parties.

We may also share personal information with third parties (including regulatory or law enforcement authorities) in order to carry out a user's request or if we believe that doing so is legally required or is in our interest to protect our property or other legal rights (including, but not limited to, enforcement of our agreements), or the rights or property of others.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/>.

Notwithstanding anything else herein, we may partner with third party advertisers who may (themselves or through their partners) place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. These cookies enable more customized ads, content or services to be provided to you. To trigger these cookies, we may pass an encrypted or “hashed” (non-human readable) identifier corresponding to your email address to a Web advertising partner, who may place a cookie on your computer. No personally identifiable information is on, or is connected to, these cookies. To opt-out of these cookies, please go to <http://www.privacychoice.org/choose>.

**If you post any of your information to a public area of our site, please be aware that it is no longer "personal information" for the purposes of this policy, and we or anyone else may use such information without restriction. If you provide access to personal or other information to a limited set of other users through any of our privacy controls or other settings, please understand that Playlist has no control over how others may collect, use or disclose such information.**

### Our Commitment to Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Please be aware, however, that no data transmissions over the Internet or other networks can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security or integrity of any information you transmit to us. You transmit information to us at your own risk. Once we receive personal information, we make reasonable efforts to protect it from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. But we cannot represent or guarantee that personal information will not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.

If Playlist learns of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. Playlist may post a notice through the service if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to access the service. Playlist may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.

Our Commitment to Children's Privacy

Playlist does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 years of age. In the event that Playlist learns it has collected any such information it will take steps immediately to delete any such information. The services are not directed at children.

### How You Can Access or Correct Your Information

You can access certain of your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by clicking on "edit" on your account page. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by changing any of the information on that page. To protect your privacy and security, we may also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

### Third-Party Sites, Software, and Services

Our services may contain links to and interoperability with third-party sites, software, and services. Any links or interoperability to third-party sites, software, or services are provided for your convenience only, and we do not have control over the content or privacy and security practices and policies of such third parties. Any personal information that you provide to our data destination partners or to other third parties is subject to that third party’s privacy practices and policies, not this policy. We encourage you to learn about their privacy and security practices and policies before providing them with personal information.

### Business Transfers

Information about our users, including personal information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, or sale of company assets, as well as in the unlikely event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personal information would be transferred as one of our business assets.

### International Visitors

This site is hosted in the United States, and we provide our services from the United States. If you use our services from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States. The United States does not have the same data protection laws as the EU and some other regions. By providing your personal information, you consent to the transfer of your personal data to the United States and the use of your personal information, in accordance with this policy.

### Information Retention and Disposal

We may retain personal information for as long as we have a business need for it or as applicable laws or regulations or government orders require us to retain it. Additionally, the service may enable you (or other users) to save information including information that you have made public or allowed certain users to access or see.

### Changes and Updates

We may occasionally update this policy. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of this policy. We encourage you to review this policy periodically to stay informed about our collection, use and disclosure of personal information.

### How To Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please send us an email at [privacy@playlist.com](mailto:privacy@playlist.com). You can also write to us at:

Playlist, Inc.  
 **Attention: Privacy Officer**  
444 High St. Suite 300  
Palo Alto, CA 94301
